# **IDRIS OJUOLAPE**

Address: Ogo Oluwa Estate, Odan Elekan, Via Olodo Bank Ibadan & Golden Estate, Ayobo-Ipaja, Lagos State.

Telephone: +2348100520099, +2347080748697

Email: oladapoojuolape@gmail.com

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

An articulate professional who can ensure that a business is financially sound, has robust accounting processes, and delivers on its financial targets. Idris has substantial accounting and Finance knowledge and possesses a real desire to succeed and make a difference. He is cost focused yet at the same time able to drive "value" and has the ability to think in new ways to get things done. Throughout his career he has used his knowledge and expertise to consistently make the right decisions. In the past he has worked for a large Microfinance bank where he has established a culture of continuous improvement by challenging existing working practices. Right now, he would like to work for a company that nurtures talent and provides its people with exciting career prospects.

_							_		
		T	<b>∽</b> 1	м.	7.1		-		
		$\mathbf{A}$	- 1	11	/ A A			7.44	
	ER	10 T	•		Æ	_	_	/=A	

Gender: Male Marital Status: Single

Nationality: Nigerian Health Status: Nigerian

**State of Origin:** Oyo **Date of Birth:** 6<sup>th</sup> May 1993

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

Tai Solarin University of Education, Ijebu-Ode, Ogun State 2016 – 2019

B.Sc. (Ed.) Accounting

Mufutau Lanihun College of Education, Ibadan, Oyo State 2010 – 2013

N.C.E. Business Education

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Apple & Pears Integrated Company, Sagamu, Ogun State**

Accountant/Finance Officer

2019 - 2021

- Generating of daily and monthly reports and daily stock preparation.
- Keep accurate records for all daily transactions
- Monthly Sock Taking and Stock balancing.
- Preparation and generating daily various bank collection and payments.
- Preparation of Journals (daily and monthly) and daily Indicator

- Preparation of Manufacturing Journal for various department production
- Posting of bank payment and receipts
- Raising of credit notes
- Raising Inventory and FOC Vouchers
- Weekly and monthly inventory control and analysis
- Posting of journal
- Tracking of sales and purchases ledger
- Posting of monthly expatriates prepayments and expenses
- Conversion of invioces to purchases journal on tally
- Process invoices
- Account receivable (generate invoice)
- Prepare monthly, quarterly and annual financial reports
- Transfer of daily finished goods and daily stock transfer into tally and excel.
- Stock Evaluation and other duties assigned by the management

### National Youth Service Corps, Ebonyi State Hope International High School, Agueke Isu

Subject Teacher (Account & Economics)

2019 - 2020

- Managed the activities of the students via proper register and attendance
- Observed students' performance and ensured students documents are well kept
- · Prepared lesson notes outline and plans in assigned subject area
- Prepared the students for both internal and external examination
- Taught students successfully & developed their love for Account & Economics

## Ibuaje Micro Finance Bank, Oshogbo, Osun State

Account Officer 2014 – 2016

- Created & monitored internal auditing procedures & to solve problem when accounting numbers are not in sync as well as cross-checked each expenses
- Managed day to day financial need of the organization.
- Managed the financial bookkeeping of a business or organization.
- Processed invoices, records payments & track expenses of the organization.
- Sent bills to customers; processes refund and works to resolve billing disputes.
- Supervised other staff members who assist with the bookkeeping duties.

# ACHIEVEMENTS AND CERTIFICATIONS Institute of Chartered Accountant of Nigeria In View Student Member Marijone Computer Training Institute, Oyo State 2010 Diploma certification in computer science and printing press

#### PERSONAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

Adhering at all times to the strictest interpretation of all relevant Codes of Practice and professional conduct with accurate recording of all cash activity on a daily basis.

A team player with outstanding oral & written communication skills and skilled in account reconciliations, bookkeeping, accrual accounting, budgeting processes, and payroll.

Can quickly understand and evaluate complex information with accurate and precise math skills as well as ability to deal with enormous quantities of financial data.

Excellent organisational skills with the capacity to deal with multiple tasks at the same time with numeracy skills, credit control, updating spreadsheets, and MS Office and Excel.

Highest standards of accounting accuracy and precision as well as familiarity with a wide range of accounting software with ability to connect with customers to build loyalty.

**REFEREES** 

**Available upon Request**